ABDUL HALIM BIN AL-RASHID

(IC:930112-07-5527)

Engineering Student

Current Address:	Block 7G-3-6, Jalan Thean Teik, 11500, Bandar Baru Ayer Itam Pulau Pinang
Mobile phone:	016-4960657
E-mail:	halim930112@yahoo.com
Nationality:	Malaysian



Personal Statement

I am currently a Graduate Trainee working in the Test Development field in Intel PSG currently my 8th month. During my time here, I had been assigned tests that I had to take care of if any problems occur. I had also been a support in numerous occasion where I will be assigned a specific colleague in his/her assignment. I had been interested in development of software and microcontroller programming (mostly on Arduino boards) which piqued my interest in this field. Throughout the semesters in Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, I had worked in different kinds of labs ranging from VLSI lab to telecommunication lab. I have skills to quickly study, analyze as well as interpreting result of experiments conducted in the labs. I had also been an excellent team player while working on projects and experiments in UTM

Education

2012-2016: Studied and graduated from University Technology Malaysia as a bachelor of electrical – electronic engineering undergraduate and taking computer engineering as a field core. Overall pointer is 3.36.

2011-2012: Studied in College Mara Kulim. Graduate with pointer of 3.70

2011: Attended National Service Programme for three months in Kedah

2009-2011: Studied in MARA Junior Science College. Graduated as first class honours student and scored 9A's in the SPM.

Working Experience

June 2016 – June 2017 Intel PSG Penang: Currently working as an engineering Graduate Trainee in the Test Development team. I had been assigned several tests under a product for me to handle. I had solved several problems (ex: setup time violation) that arises which enables the product to function properly. Other than that, I had also been assigned as a support in numerous occasion. I had helped my colleagues on solving their test related issue as a support.

June 2015 – September 2015 Agilent Penang: Worked as a technical intern during the internship period. One of the projects consist me on program a software which automatically collects data from an Excel file, tabulate and send the graphs of the data to specified user using Excel Macro programming language. I had also entered the manufacturing area to observe and build a machine unit. I had also been involved in testing the machine before packaging. Other than that, I had also been placed in a team where our task is to design a proper way to ease in monitoring items in and out of warehouse.

Skills and Achievements

Languages: Good conversational and writing of both English and Bahasa Malaysia. Scored a band 5 for oral efficiency and a band 4 in writing skills during TECS. Can understand Tamil and basic oral proficiency in the language.

Computer Languages: C/C++: Used this language to for microcontroller programming especially Arduino UNO and Intel Edison. Currently enrolled in Innovate Malaysia competition, where one of the competition rules is to program Intel Edison board using C/C++.

:Excel Macro: I had studied this language and implemented the language in a project during my internship in Agilent Penang.

:MIT app inventor 2: Used this language to make personal application to aid on Arduino development projects.

 $HTML, CSS, Javas\, cript: I had \, studied \, and \, used \, this \, language \, to \, build \, simple \, we bpages \, for \, personal \, enrichment.$

Karate: Was a yellow belt member of Karate Association UTM. Hosted and participated the Annual Karate Graduation Ceremony which involves guests from Singapore, Malaysia and Japan.

Peer Counselling: Had been a member of Peer Counselling UTM. Had been involved in a visit orphanage as a part of the peer counselling program to provide study tips for the pupil of the orphanages. Had also attended course on mental health organised by UTM peer counselling club.

Hiking: Was a member of the hiking club in UTM. Attended a hiking expedition to Gunung Datuk Rembau located in Negeri Sembilan for two days.

Deejay: During my 4th year first semester in UTM, I had become one of the two first radio deejays in UTM. I had interviewed the TNC and the faculty dean during the radio session.

Final Year Project: Won a Gold Medal in UTM's Electrical Engineering Student Showcase for my final year project entitled Smart Irrigation System with Remote Monitoring.

Hobbies and Interests

Making Flower via Beads: I had made several flowers by using beads and successfully sold some of them customers around Penang.

Blogging: I had made several projects and posted it on Instructables website and personal blog (http://startingwitharduino.blogspot.my/). Two of my projects were featured in the Instructables website with overtotal of 11,000 views.

Reading: I have read many types of books which enriches my vocabulary and efficiency in English. During my holidays, I helped my little sister on her English homework and encouraged her reading English books.

Tinkering: During my free time, I will carry out projects on my own mainly using Arduino microcontroller. These projects that I had carried out will be posted online in the Instructables website and on my personal blog.

Jogging/Marathon: I would always go for a run on the evenings. While I was studying in matriculation, I had become a runner for 4 x 100m and won the third place. During my first year in UTM, I had joined a marathon organised by the student council and won a place in the top 20.